A Guide to the Arthur M. Squires Papers, 1888-1987 (Bulk 1940-1986)
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Arthur M. Squires Papers, 1888-1987 (Bulk 1940-1986).
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms87-006
72 cu. ft.; 72 boxes
Squires, Arthur M., 1916-
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
University Distinguished Professor Emeritus (1986- ) at Virginia Tech. Member, National Academy of Engineering. Fellow, American Academy of Arts and Sciences. Educated at University of Missouri (A.B. 1938) and Cornell University (Ph.D. 1947). Employment: M.W. Kellogg Company (the Kellex Corporation), 1942-46, participating in design and startup of gaseous diffusion plant at Oak Ridge; Hydrocarbon Research, Inc. of New York City, 1946-59, architect-engineering firm (research laboratories at Trenton, New Jersey) catering to petroleum, chemical, and steel industries; self-employed consultant, 1959-67; faculty of chemical engineering, The City College of The City University of New York (1967-76), Department Chairman (1970-73), Distinguished University Professor (1974-76); Frank C. Vilbrandt Professor of Chemical Engineering (1976-82) and University Distinguished Professor (1978-86), Virginia Polytechnic Institute & State University. Consultant for U.S. Bureau of Mines, Office of Coal Research, Electric Power Research Institute, United Nations, Office of Technology Assessment, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, and others. Author of The Tender Ship: Governmental Management of Technological Change (1986). Expert in fluid beds, petroleum refining, hydrocarbon synthesis, coal conversions (gasification, liquefaction, carbonization, combustion), iron ore reduction, low-temperature processes, dust filtration, air pollution control.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of extensive correspondence, unpublished research reports, lectures, trip reports, reprints, trip diaries (1968-82), photographs (1979) from his trip to China, daily work books (1959-81), and subject files spanning entire career. This collection is unprocessed.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in six series: A Series-Subject Files; B Series-Publications; C Series-Correspondence Files; D Series-Diaries; E Series-Materials to go with the Walter E. Lobo/M. W. Kellogg Files (transferred to Lobo Papers, Ms85-014); and F Series: Books for Archives.
Please note: There is no Box 10.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Separated Materials
Box E-1 was transferred to the Walter E. Lobo Papers, 1929-1955, Ms85-014 in November 1987. The box contained:
"The Improbable Achievement: Chemical Engineering at MIT"
"Large Scale Production of Oxygen - Combined Technical Oil Missions Holroyd Report - German Oil Technology"
"Guide to Refinery Operating Costs (Process Costimating)"
"The German Chemical Industry - A Bibliography of the Chemical, Metallurgical, and Process Industries"
"Enriched Air"
"List of Process Management's Translations of I. G. Reports - Set No. 46"
Index Terms
Local Subjects:
Faculty; Science and Technology; University Archives
Subjects:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- A Series, Subject Files, 1888-1985, n.d.
  - Box A-1, 1948-1974, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Acetylene, 1955-1967.
    - Acetylene, BASF, 1954-1955.
    - Acetylene, Low Temperature Recovery.
    - Acetylene, Sand Quench Rates, 1948.
    - Acid Rain, 1980-1981.
    - Active Carbon, 1962.
    - Adhesion, 1961.
    - Adsorption, 1962.
    - Aerosols, Beams, Kinetics, Research, Particulates, 1966-1980.
    - Aerosols, Beams, Kinetics, Research, Particulates, 1966-1980.
    - Air Compressors, 1968.
    - Air Pollution, Sources, Controls, Conferences, Monitoring Equipment, 1966-1973.
    - Air Pollution, Motor Vehicle Emissions, Fog, Smoking, Carbon Monoxide Levels, 1966-1969.
    - Air Pollution, Sources, Controls, Effects on Vegetation & Health, Air Quality Studies, 1961-1974.
    - Air Pollution, Sources, Controls, Effects on Vegetation & Health, Air Quality Studies, 1961-1974.
    - Air Pollution, Clean Power, Coal Fired Plants, Alter. Fuel Sources, B&W/Shell Reports, 1967-1972.
    - Air Pollution Control, Air Quality, Control Equip., Emissions, Effects of Pollution, 1963-1973.
    - Air Pollution Control, Air Quality, Control Equip., Emissions, Effects of Pollution, 1961-1975.
    - Air Pollution Control, Florides, 1973.
    - Air Pollution Control, Pollutants in Gas Plumes, 1973.
    - Air Pollution Control Assoc. (APCA) Abstracts, 1961-1970.
    - APCA Abstracts, 1962-1972.
    - APCA Abstracts, 1961-1969.
    - APCA Abstracts, 1961-1969.
    - Air Pollution, Control Cost Reports, 1969.
    - Air Pollution, List of Attendees at National Conference, 1966.
  - Box A-2,1946-1977, n.d. (Box 2)
    - Air Pollution, Nitrogen Oxides, Control of, 1966-1970.
    - Air Pollution, Odor, Measurement of, 1968.
    - Air Pollution Training Grants, 1966-1967.
    - Air Preheaters, Designs, 1970.
    - Air Quality, 1967-1977.
    - Air Separation, Oxygen Production Methods/Drawings, 1951-1967.
    - Air Separation, Reversing Exchangers, Reports, 1947-1951, n.d.
    - Air Separation, Graphs of Expander Characteristics, n.d.
    - Air Separation, Kwauk Air Fractionation Report, 1956.
    - Air Separation, Gas Turbines, Reports on, 1946-1956.
    - Air Separation, Regenerators, Patent Application, 1955.
    - Air Separation, Technical Data, 1946-1947.
    - Alumina, Properties of, Heat of Wetting, 1952-1956.
    - Aluminum, Processing of, 1960, 1974.
    - Ammonia, Reports: J. Kjaer, Achorn/Walkup, Stotler/Squires, Squires, Zenz, 1947-1974.
    - Ammonia, Kinetics of Ammonia Synthesis, Various Reports, 1945-1948.
    - Ammonia, Demand Forecast Report, Catalyst Catalog, Aspects of Ammonia Plants, Transportation of, M. W. Kellogg Drawings.
    - Ammonia Synthesis, Converters, Demand Forecast, Technology Adv., 1964 Kellogg Notebook, n.d.-1964.
    - Ammonia Synthesis, Studies, Reports, Plant Designs, Drawings, 1948-1974.
    - Ammonia Synthesis, Kinetics, Processes, Plants, 1970 Kleinfeld Report, Kellogg Data, 1962-1970.
    - Atmospheric Chemicals, 1974.
    - Atmospheric Studies, Auto/Other Pollution Sources, AMBIO Journals, 1970-1972.
    - Atom Bomb Politics, Squires/Cuthbert Daniel/Editorial Corres., "World Disarmament," 1946-1948.
    - Atom Bomb Politics, 1947 Princeton Conference, Various Publications, 1946-1948.
    - Auto Exhaust Control, 1979 Steam-Powered Vehicles, Trans. Controls, 1968-1979.
    - Azeotropic Distillation, 1945.
    - Balance of Payments, Costs of Technology, 1970-1973.
    - Bins (Bunkers), 1962.
    - Biomass, Energy Forests, Synthetic Fuels, 1973, 1976.
    - Biomedical Engineering, 1968.
    - Bubbles, Flow of, Migration, Velocity, Absorption, Other Characteristics, 1966-1977.
    - Calculator Advertisement, n.d.
    - Calcium Sulfate Reduction Patent, 1972.
  - Box A-3, 1946-1978. (Box 3)
    - Carbon, Characteristics, Properties, NSF Proposal, 1951-1972.
    - Carbon, Characteristics, Properties, NSF Proposal, 1951-1972.
    - Carbon Black, Bibliography, 1953.
    - Carbon Dioxide Scrubbing, 1948-1969.
    - Carbon Dioxide Scrubbing, Flour's Process, 1959-1961.
    - Carbon Dioxide Scrubbing, Processes, Reports on, 1952-1958.
    - Carbon Dioxide Scrubbing, Processes, Reports on, 1952-1958.
    - Carbon Dioxide Scrubbing, Hydrocarbon Research Institute (HRI) Pilot Plant, 1956.
    - Carbon Dioxide Scrubbing, HRI Pilot Plant, 1959.
    - Carbon Dioxide Scrubbing, HRI Commercial Plant, 1957.
    - Carbon Dioxide Scrubbing, Hot Potassium Carbonate Process, 1960, 1962.
    - Carbon Dioxide Scrubbing, Mono-Ethanolamine (MEA), 1949-1961.
    - Carbon Dioxide Scrubbing, Rectisol Process, 1956.
    - Carbon Dioxide Scrubbing, Vetracoke Process, 1958.
    - Carbon Dioxide Scrubbing, Water Process, 1947-1951.
    - Carbon Monoxide, 1968.
    - Carbon Monoxide, Control of, 1966-1970.
    - Carbon Monoxide Scrubbing, 1957, 1960.
    - Catalytic Polymerization, 1948, 1956.
    - Catalysis, 1946-1975.
    - Catalysis, Roles, Trends, Advances, 1965-1970.
    - Cement, 1960-1962.
    - Cement, 1967, 1971.
    - Chemical Engineering Education, 1968.
    - Chemicals from Coal, 1960-1978.
    - Chlorine, n.d.
    - Chloro-Hydrocarbon Pollution, 1972.
    - Chromatography, 1968, 1878.
    - Classification, 1963-1964.
    - Claus Process, Sulfur Removal, 1949-1969.
    - Climate, Effects on, Changes in, 1971-1975.
    - Climate, Cities, 1970.
    - Coal Abstracts, "Chemical Abstracts," n.d.
    - Coal, Technical Data, 1965-1968.
    - Coal, Conversion to Other Forms of Fuel, 1964-1969.
    - Coal, Anthracite, Various Reports, 1954-1981.
    - Coal, Ash, 1954-1977.
    - Coal, Trash Elements, 1962-1976.
    - Coal, Carbonization, Report by Samuel Dobner, 1975.
  - Box A-4, 1939-1980. (Box 4)
    - Coal, Carbonization, 1960-1970.
    - Coal, Carbonization, 1966-1982.
    - Coal, Carbonization, 1955-1977.
    - Coal, Carbonization, Ziesecke Thesis, 1939.
    - Coal, Carbonization, Decaking Patent, 1967.
    - Coal, Carbonization, FMC Corporation, 1971-1974.
    - Coal, Carbonization, FMC Corporation, 1966-1970.
    - Coal, Carbonization, FMC Corporation, 1968-1972.
    - Coal, Carbonization, Flash Pyrolysis (Rapid Heating), 1964-1975.
    - Coal, Carbonization, Flash Pyrolysis (Rapid Heating), 1977-1985.
    - Coal, Carbonization, Foster-Pegg Method, 1957-1967.
    - Coal, Carbonization, Garrett's Coal Pyrolysis Process, 1974.
    - Coal, Carbonization, Hydrocarbon Research, Inc., 1947-1949.
    - Coal, Carbonization, American Lurgi Corporation Lurgi Ruhrgas Process, 1966.
    - Coal, Carbonization, Parry Process (Low Temperature Carbonization), 1956-1968.
    - Coal, Carbonization, Project Seacoke, 1969.
    - Coal, Chemical Structure, 1961-1980.
  - Box A-5, 1922-1983, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Coal, Chemical Structure, 1972-1977.
    - Coal, Chemical Structure, 1968-1982.
    - Coal, Chemical Structure, Sulfur, 1976.
    - Coal, Combustion, 1966-1983.
    - Coal, Combustion, Emissions, 1965-1980.
    - Coal, Combustion, Fluid Bed Reactions, 1970-1979.
    - Coal, Combustion, Fluid Bed Reactions, 1969-1982.
    - Coal, Combustion, Fluid Bed Reactions, 1977-1980.
    - Coal, Combustion, Magnetohydrodynamics, 1967.
    - Coal, Combustion, Spontaneous Heating, n.d.
    - Coal, Combustion, Gas Turbines, 1975.
    - Coal, Combustion, Oil/Coal Mixtures, General Motors Reports, 1976, n.d.
    - Coal, Desulfurization, 1922-1976.
    - Coal, Desulfurization, 1960-1978.
    - Coal, Desulfurization, (Solv Ref?), 1964-1969.
    - Coal, Development, Western United States, 1971-1973.
    - Coal, Dryers, 1957-1976.
    - Coal, Drying, 1950-1977.
    - Coal, Fly Ash Formation, 1976-1977.
    - Coal, Gases, 1972.
  - Box A-6, 1947-1975, n.d. (Box 6)
    - Coal, Gasification (Gas), Bituminous Coal Research, 1966-1975.
    - Coal, Gas, U. S. Bureau of Mines, 1964-1973.
    - Coal, Gas, Combined Cycle, 1970-1972.
    - Coal, Gas, Consolidation Coal Company (CCC), 1964-1975.
    - Coal, Gas, CCC, 1955-1968.
    - Coal, Gas, CCC, 1970-1971.
    - Coal, Gas, CCC, 1973.
    - Coal, Gas, Electrofluidic Processing, 1967.
    - Coal, Gas, Entrained Bed Gasification, 1976.
    - Coal, Flash Steam Pyrolysis, 1984.
    - Coal, Gas, Fluid Bed Patent and Article, 1937, 1969.
    - Coal, Gas, Fluid Beds, Commercial, 1958-1959.
    - Coal, Gas, Fluid Beds, Commercial, 1959.
    - Coal, Gas, Fluid Bed Pilot Plant, 1957-1958.
    - Coal, Gas, Fluid Bed Pilot Plant, 1955-1957.
    - Coal, Gas, Gumz, Wilhelm; 1809-1834 Encyclopedia Photocopies, 1947-n.d.
    - Coal, Gas, General Information (Gen), 1959-1975.
  - Box A-7, 1936-1981, n.d. (Box 7)
    - Coal, Gas, General Information (Gen), 1965.
    - C. H. Secord Patent Application.
    - Coal, Gas, Gen, 1976.
    - Coal, Gas, Gen, 1960-1974.
    - Coal, Gas, Gen, 1977-1985.
    - Coal, Gas, Gen, Report by Wilhelm Gumz, 1949.
    - Coal, Gas, Gen, 1936-n.d.
    - Coal, Gas, Gen, 1958-1977.
    - Coal, Gas, Gen, 1977-1978.
    - Coal, Gas, Gen, 1953-1976.
    - Coal, Gas, Gumz, Wilhelm, 1971-1973.
    - Coal, Gas, Grand Forks, North Dakota, 1964.
    - Coal, Gas, Hydrocarbon Research, Inc., 1958.
    - Coal, Gas, Institute of Gas Technology, 1953-1978.
    - Coal, Gas, Institute of Gas Technology, 1970-1972.
    - Coal, Gas, M. W. Kellogg Company, 1964-1973.
    - Coal, Gas, Kinetics, 1947-1979.
    - Coal, Gas, Kinetics, 1946-1981.
    - Box A-23, 1928-1979, n.d. (Box 23)
      - Manuscripts, Drafts of Talks and "Coal Energy" Book, 1976, 1979.
      - Manuscripts, Princeton Lectures.
      - Manuscripts, South Africa Lectures.
      - Manuscripts, South Africa Lectures.
      - Manuscripts, Unlabeled.
      - Manuscripts, Unlabeled.
      - Manuscripts, Unlabeled.
      - Manuscripts, Unlabeled, 1973, n.d.
      - Manuscripts, 1976-1977.
      - Mass Transfer, 1948-1966.
      - Materials Construction, 1967.
      - Materials Construction, 1967.
      - Materials Construction, 1974.
      - Materials Construction, 1945-1976.
      - Measure Standard, 1965-1969.
      - Meeting Attendees, 1968-1972.
      - Membrane Separation, 1970.
      - Mercury, 1969-1978.
      - Metallurgy, 1950-1958.
      - Metals Pollution, 1972-1973.
      - Methanation, 1962, 1964.
      - Methane Pyrolysis, 1966.
      - Methanol, 1970, 1977.
      - Methane Synthesis, 1948-1976.
      - Magnetohydrodynamics, Power Generation, 1959-1972.
      - Military Draft, 1968.
      - Mine Drainage, 1969-n.d.
      - Miscellaneous, Correspondence, 1947-1948.
      - Mist Collectors, 1968.
      - Molecular Sieve Adsorbent, 1967.
      - Natural Gas, 1962-1980.
  - Box A-8, 1947-1982, n.d. (Box 8)
    - Coal, Gas, Kinetics (Fluid Bed), 1947-1979.
    - Coal, Gas, Kinetics (Fluid Bed), 1947-1979.
    - Coal, Gas, Liege Conference, 1954.
    - Coal, Gas, Lurgi Coal Gasification Plants, n.d.-1980.
    - Coal, Gas, Lurgi Coal Gasification Plants, 1954-1974.
    - Coal, Gas, Lurgi Process/Slag Results, 1958-1962.
    - Coal, Gas, Lurgi Process/Slag Results, 1957-1965.
    - Coal, Gas, Molten Iron, 1972.
    - Coal, Gas, Nuclear Heat, 1960-1962.
    - Coal, Gas, Peat, 1954-1977.
    - Coal, Gas, Producers, 1972-n.d.
    - Coal, Gas, Rummel-Otto, 1956-1959.
    - Coal, Gas, Russian (Like Constructors John Brown), 1956-1973.
    - Coal, Gas, Shell Coal Gasification Meeting, 1985.
    - Coal, Gas, Slagging Gasification Processes, 1965-1975.
    - Coal, Gas, Synthetic Natural Gas, 1972-n.d.
    - Coal, Gas, Squires, Arthur M., 1961, 1967.
    - Coal, Gas, Suspension, 1954-1970.
    - Coal, Gas, Technical Data, 1947, 1948, 1923.
    - Coal, Gas, Texaco, 1949.
    - Coal, Gas, Underground Gasification, 1947-1975.
    - Coal, Gas, Underground, 1963-1984.
    - Coal, Gas, Wellman-Galusha, 1947-n.d.
    - Coal, Gas, Winkler Process, 1932-1982.
    - Coal, Gas, Westinghouse Gasification Process, 1972-1982.
  - Box A-9, 1938-1983, n.d. (Box 9)
    - Coal, General Information (Gen), 1959-1973.
    - Coal, Gen, 1960-1982.
    - Coal, Gen, 1967-1979.
    - Coal, Gen, 1974-1983.
    - Coal, Gen, 1956-1973.
    - Coal, Gen, 1966-1975.
    - Coal, Gen, 1964-1968.
    - Coal, Gen, 1960-1970.
    - Coal, Gen, 1961-1985.
    - Coal, Ash Viscosity, 1959.
    - Coal, Lignite, 1963, n.d.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, 1938-1973.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, Blackwood, 1966-1970.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, U. S. Bureau of Mines, 1962-1973.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, Consolidation Coal Company, 1965.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, Dent's Scheme, 1947-1958.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, Ferrous Sulphide, 1972.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, Flash Data, 1962-1982.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, Gen, 1978-1979.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, Gen, 1977-1979.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, Gen, 1968-1979.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, Gen, 1961-1978.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, Hyrdocarbon Research, Inc., 1948-1970.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, Institute of Gas Technology, 1958-1965.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, Kinetics, 1947-1975.
    - Coal, Hydrogenation, Union Carbide, 1952.
    - Coal, Liquefaction, 1929-1980.
    - Coal, Liquefaction, 1971-1983.
    - Coal, Liquefaction, 1961-n.d.
    - Coal, Liquefaction, Solvent Refined Coal, 1974-n.d.
    - Coal, Liquefaction, Solvent Refined Coal.
    - Coal, Liquefaction, Solvent Refined Coal.
    - Coal, Liquefaction, Chapter of Coal Liquefaction Text, 1977.
    - Coal, Liquefaction, Chapter of Coal Liquefaction Text, 1978.
    - Coal, Liquefaction, Kroenig Monograph, 1950.
  - Box A-11, 1925-1985, n.d. (Box 11)
    - Coal, Liquefaction, 1977-n.d.
    - Coal, Liquefaction, 1967-1979.
    - Coal, Mining, 1956-1975.
    - Coal, Mining, 1965-n.d.
    - Coal, Origins, n.d.-1979.
    - Coal, Oxidation, 1963-1966.
    - Coal, Passivating, 1973.
    - Coal, Petrography, 1968, 1971.
    - Coal, Preparation of, 1974, n.d.
    - Coal Reserves (U. S.), 1975.
    - Coal Reserves (U. S.), 1925-1980.
    - Coal, Steam Flash, 1968.
    - Coal, Supercritical Extraction, 1971-1985.
    - Coal, Supercritical Extraction, A. K. Sunol Thesis, 1982.
    - Coal, Tar Bases, 1962.
    - Coal, Trace Elements, 1974-1980.
    - Coal, Thermochemistry, 1976, n.d.
    - Coal, Washing, 1974-1981.
    - Coke, General Information, 1947-1969.
    - Coke, Manufacture, FMC Coke Process, 1966, n.d.
    - Coke, Manufacture, Peabody and Other Processes, 1952-1982.
    - Coke, Desulfurization, 1960.
  - Box A-12, 1937-1982, n.d. (Box 12)
    - Combustion, R. R. Paxton Thesis, 1949.
    - Combustion, A. C. Faatz, Jr.; R. R. Hughes Thesis, 1947.
    - Combustion, General Information, 1962-1973.
    - Combustion, General Information, 1937-1982.
    - Combustion, 1946-1984.
    - Combustion, 1940-1953.
    - Combustion, Magnetohydrodynamics, 1972.
    - Combustion, Pulverized Fuel, 1958-1975.
    - Combustion, Slag Furnaces, 1938-1954.
    - Combustion, Submerged, 1956.
    - Compressors, 1954-1964.
    - Conservation, 1977-1978.
    - Cooling Tower, 1971.
    - Copper, 1970.
    - Corrosion, 1947-1974.
    - Cost Estimates, 1955-1971.
    - Desalination, 1963-1969.
    - Desalinzation, 1967.
    - Deuterium, Heavy Water, 1955, 1960.
    - Differential Scanning, Calorimetry, n.d.-1974.
    - Distillation, 1964.
    - District Heating, Sweden, 1975.
    - District Heating, 1974-1978.
    - District Heating, 1972-1977.
    - District Heating, 1970-1977.
    - District Heating, 1970-1979.
    - District Heating, 1977-1978.
  - Box A-13, 1888-1981, n.d. (Box 13)
    - District Heating, 1978-1979.
    - Dolomite, 1959-1971.
    - Dolomite, 1912-1972.
    - Dolomite, 1960-1972.
    - Dry Cooling Towers, 1969-1980.
    - Dry Cooling Towers, 1970-1980.
    - Dry Cooling Towers, 1970, n.d.
    - Dust Control, 1888-1978.
    - Dust Control, 1960-1969.
    - Dust Control, Filters, 1952-1975.
    - Dust Control, Filters, 1929-1976.
    - Dust Control, Filters, 1965-1976.
    - Dust Control, Filters, 1952-1981.
    - Dust Explosion, 1968.
    - Dust Scrubbers, 1948-1970.
  - Box A-14, 1921-1977, n.d. (Box 14)
    - Dust Scrubbers, 1973-1983.
    - Ebullated Beds, 1961, 1967.
    - Economic Growth, Limits, 1969-1972.
    - Electrogasdynamic Generators, 1966-1968.
    - Electricity, Generating of, 1961-1965.
    - Electrostatic Precipitation, 1961-1974.
    - Energy, 1969-1973.
    - Energy, 1970-1975.
    - Energy, 1972-1974.
    - Energy, 1969-1973.
    - Energy, n.d.-1976.
    - Energy, 1971-1975.
    - Energy, 1965-1975.
    - Energy, 1921-1975.
    - Energy, 1972-1977.
    - Energy, 1976.
  - Box A-15, 1967-1977, n.d. (Box 15)
    - Energy, 1967-1968.
    - Energy in Agriculture, 1975-1977.
    - Energy in Agriculture, 1976, n.d.
    - Energy Conservation, 1973-1975.
    - Energy Corridor, 1972.
    - Energy Demands, 1968-1973.
    - Energy Demands, 1971.
    - Energy Policy, 1970-1976.
    - Energy Policy, 1975-1976.
    - Energy Policy, 1970-1973.
    - Energy Policy, n.d.-1972.
    - Energy Policy, 1971-1975.
    - Energy Policy, 1971-1973.
    - Energy Policy, Gordon Manuscript.
  - Box A-16, 1963-1977. (Box 16)
    - Energy Policy, 1971-1973.
    - Energy Policy, 1971-1972.
    - Energy Policy, 1971-1975.
    - Energy Policy, Cornell Report, 0197-1971.
    - Energy Policy, 1968-1973.
    - Energy Policy Project, 1972-1973.
    - Energy Resources, 1972-1977.
    - Energy Resources, 1970-1973.
    - Energy Resources, 1965-1977.
    - Energy Resources, Solar, 1971-1972.
    - Energy Storage, 1969, 1974.
    - Energy Technology, Drexel Reports, 1971.
    - Environment, 1965-1968.
    - Environment, 1958-1971.
    - Environment, 1968-1969.
    - Environment, 1965-1971.
    - Environment, 1964-1975.
    - Environment, 1963-1971.
  - Box A-17, 1962-1985, n.d. (Box 17)
    - Environment, 1966-1974.
    - Environment, Delson/Frankel Report, 1971.
    - Environmental Chemicals, 1972.
    - Environmental Impact, 1971.
    - Environment, Mercury in, 1971.
    - Environment, Toxic Chemicals, 1973.
    - Equipressure Reforming, 1965.
    - Examinations, 2 Copies, 1976.
    - Fibers, 1962-1969.
    - Filtration, 1969-1977.
    - Fine Particulate Scrubbing, 1974.
    - Fixed Beds, 1963-1967.
    - Flash Smelting, 1955.
    - Fluidized-Bed Coal Combustion, Lime Additives, 1976.
    - Fluidized Beds, Electrochemistry, 1967 (?).
    - Fluid Particle Systems, Bibliography.
    - Fluid Flow, 1947-1977.
    - Fluid Bed Roasting, 1956-1964.
    - Fluidized Solids, Fluid Bed Combustion, 1970-1972, n.d.
    - Fluidized Solids, Elliott Report.
    - Fluidized Solids, Fluid Bed Boilers, 1972-1973.
    - Fluidized Solids, Fluid Bed Boilers, 1968-1974.
    - Fluidized Solids, Fluid Bed Boilers: Exxon Report, 1976.
    - Fluidized Solids, Fluid Bed Boilers, 1981-1985.
    - Fluidized Solids, M. S. Kwauk Thesis, 1947.
    - Fluidized Solids, Lurgi Fast Bed Process, 1982.
    - Fluid Transport.
    - Fly Ash, 1966-1969.
    - Flywheels, 1970.
    - Food, 1962-1975.
    - Food, 1967-1973.
  - Box A-18, 1942, 1984, n.d. (Box 18)
    - Fractionation, 1949-1956.
    - Fractionation, 1948, 1951.
    - Fractionation, 1952-1965.
    - Fusion, 1971-1977.
    - Gas Absorption, 1948-1968.
    - Gas Adsorption, 1946-1968.
    - Gaseous Diffusion, 1967-1973.
    - Gaseous Diffusion, 1966-1977.
    - Gaseous Diffusion, 1946-1984.
    - Gaseous Diffusion, 1942-1982.
    - Gaseous Diffusion, 1946-1948.
    - Gas-Liquid Flow, 1963.
    - Gas-Solid Reactions, Kinetics, 1960-n.d.
    - Gas Turbines, 1958-1979.
    - Gas Turbines, 1946-1959.
    - Gas Turbines, 1958-1977.
    - Gas Turbines, Patent Descriptions, 1938-1949.
    - Gas Turbine Patents, Fuel Gas Supply, 1916-1961.
    - Gas Turbine Patents, Steam Addition, 1908-1959.
    - Gas Turbines, Coal Fired, 1954-1964.
    - Geothermal, Energy Fields, 1972-n.d.
    - Graff, Union Carbide Research Report, 1967.
    - Gravity Flow of Solids, 1964-1968.
    - Grinding Processes, n.d.-1980.
    - Heat Transfer, 1946-1980.
  - Box A-19, 1946-1984, n.d. (Box 19)
    - Heat Transfer, Beds, 1948-1961.
    - Heat Transfer, Fins, 1947-n.d.
    - Heat Transfer, Regenerators, 1949-1953.
    - Heat Transfer, Regenerators, 1947-1984.
    - Heat Transfer, Flat Plate Exchanger, 1949.
    - Helium, 1958-1974.
    - History of Technology, 1962-1969.
    - History of Technology, 1961-1976.
    - History of Technology, 1962-1984.
    - History of Technology, n.d.-1984.
    - Hydrocracking, 1946-1970.
    - Hydrocracking, Flexicoking, 1953-1974.
    - Hydrogen Cyanide, 1955.
    - Hydrodealkylation, 1960-1968.
    - Hydrogen Fuels, 1972.
    - Hydrogen Fuels, 1972-1974.
    - Hydrocarbon, Oxidation, 1948-1949.
    - Hydrocarbons, Reforming, 1963.
    - Hydrogen Sulfide, Acceptors, 1974-1976.
    - Hydrogen Sulfide, Control, 1972.
    - Hydrogen Sulfide, Scrubbing, 1946-1970.
    - Hydrogen Sulfide, Scrubbing.